Finding Aid for Glynn Family Papers, 1934-1992
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Glynn Family papers 1934-1992
Glynn Family.
0.75 linear ft.
9512 Aa 2
Alphrett and Mary Ann Glynn family, settlers to Millington Township, Tuscola County, Michigan. Papers relating to the history of the family; family reunion records including letters from family members unable to attend reunion; some of these letters are from family serving in the military during World War II; also photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
This collection was donated to the Bentley Library by Ellen Thornton Hoffrichter (donor no. 7337 ) in July 1994.
The collection is open to research.
Alphrett Jasper Glynn and Mary Ann Glynn moved to the state of Michigan in the fall of 1854 from their home in Ohio. They travelled through Toledo and Flint, where they purchased a section of land in Millington Township. Alphrett Glynn left his wife and two small children with friends in Arbela, Michigan, while he went to prepare their new home. The Glynn family moved in the spring of 1855 and was one of the first families to settle in Millington Township (later Watertown Township) in Tuscola County.
The Glynns had 12 children, 3 of whom died in infancy. Their main occupation was farming, but Alphrett Glynn also owned a peddling wagon from which he sold groceries, hardware and novelties. He was also one of the first in the area to have a horse-powered grain separator and a team of horses to operate it. Glynn was also the first road commissioner who laid out roads from Homer Beaches to Duncan Corners. Glynn was very active in the community and held several public offices.
The family grew and dispersed. Many stayed in Michigan, but others moved as far away as Washington state. They kept in touch with each other through letters and an annual family reunion, held every year since 1934 in Michigan.
This collection chronicles the lives of members of the Glynn family through letters and records of the annual family reunion. While there are very few items from the early years of their settlement in Michigan, there is a great deal of information on the children and grandchildren of Alphrett and Mary Ann.
The collection is arranged into three series, Family History, Family Reunion, and Photographs.
Subjects:
Glynn, Alphrett.; Glynn, Mary Ann.; Glynn family.; Millington (Mich.: Township); Tuscola County (Mich.); World War, 1939-1945.; Women--Michigan--Millington (Township)
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Glynn family.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Tintypes.
- Family History
  The Family History series contains written family histories, family trees and early correspondence.
  - Correspondence, 1888 (Box 1)
  - Family Descendants (Box 1)
  - Settlement in Michigan (Box 1)
- Family Reunion
  The Family Reunion series is the largest and contains mostly correspondence from family members not able to attend the annual family reunion. These letters were read at the reunion. The letters provide a look at the lives of family members from the 1930s to the 1980s. The letters from those who stayed in Michigan provide commentaries on life in Michigan for over half a century. There is a group of letters from family members who served overseas during World War II, which provides a glimpse at the war through their eyes. The letters are arranged chronologically by the name of the reunion secretary and alphabetically by the sender of the letter. The reunion record book includes minutes, financial records, and mailing lists for every family reunion held from 1946 to 1992.
  - Reunion Secretary
    - Ella Owens
      - Letter from Civilian Thornton, 1935 (Box 1)
      - Letters from Lois Bryner, 1934, 1937-1938 (Box 1)
      - Letters from Ella Bulloch, 1932-1937 (Box 1)
    - Clark Summers
      - Letters, 1941-1949, 3 folders (Box 1)
      - Letters from Lois Bryner, 1941, 1943, 1945, 1947-1948 (Box 1)
      - Letters from Ella Bulloch, 1940, 1943-1945, 1947 (Box 1)
      - Letters from Jennie Glynn, 1939, 1941-1945, 1947 (Box 1)
      - Letters from Roy Glynn, 1944-1945 (Box 1)
      - Letters from Wilbur Glynn, 1942-1945 (Box 1)
    - Cecil Summers
      - Letters, 1950-1958 (Box 1)
      - Letters from Lois Bryne, 1949, 1951, 1953, 1956 (Box 1)
      - Letters from Jennie Glynn, 1949-1953 (Box 1)
    - Frederick Whitcomb
      - Letters, 1959-1960, 1962 (Box 1)
    - Unidentified
      - Letters, 1964-1966, 1968-1970, 1972, 1974 (Box 1)
    - Margaret Davies
      - Letters, 1977, 1981-1989 (Box 1)
  - Reunion Record Book
    - 1946-1972, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - 1976-1990 (Box 1)
  - Mailing Lists, 1972, 1985, 1994 (Box 1)
- Photographs
  The Photographs series provides identified portraits of family members.
  - Portraits and snapshots of family members, 2 folders and 1 photograph album (Box 1)